#大家好 隔壁家老李的那個玉米呀
Hi everyone. Our neighbour, Li, his corns,
#被他摘 摘了還剩下一點點了
he has picked, picked but some are left.
#他叫我去摘 摘一點來餵豬
He asked us to pick, to pick some for our pigs.
#那些可能有點是次品 他不要的
Perhaps those are substandard and he doesn't want them.
#我們去摘 就在這一大片都是玉米地
So here we go. This whole area is corn field.
#剛好叫我弟過來
I've just asked by little brother to come,
#幫我扛一下 扛 扛那個玉米回家
to carry, to carry the corns back home.
#最近腰痛
I have back pain recently.
#你看 這裡有一個哦
Look! Here is one.
#哇 這個很靚的 這個
Wa! This is beautiful, this is...
#哇
Wa!
#好香
Smells good!
#你看 這一個
Look! This one...
#拿袋裝起來
Put it into the bag.
#啊 這裡有一個
Ah! Here is one.
#那麼小的
It's so small.
#你看
Look!
#隔壁的老李 摳的很
The neighbour Li, what a stingy guy!
#全部大的都被摘完啦
He has picked all the big ones.
#只剩下這個 那麼小的
Only the, the small ones are left for me.
#這個肉都不知道有沒有的
I wonder if there is anything to eat.
#你看 一半都沒肉的
Look! It's half empty.
#啊 上面有一點
Ah! There is a bit at the tip.
#你看 這有一個
Look! Here is one.
#老李摘得太乾淨啦
Li has picked too thoroughly.
#你看 都沒有
Look! None here!
#都沒有那個小玉米啦
I can't see any small corns.
#我們砍點那個 這個
Let's chop some, I mean, this is
#玉米杆啊 回去喂[SIC]竹鼠
corn stalks, for our bamboo rats.
#那竹鼠很喜歡吃的哦
The bamboo rats like it very much.
#這個秆很好的哦 (註︰杆和秆也有出現，我也不知道哪個才是正確)
This stalk is nice.
#這個 一根一根
Here, one by one.
#吶 就這樣把它 (註︰這句和上一句不知他想說甚麼)
Na, then we can...
#這個是 壞的
This is, rotten.
#這個秆子有點甜的
This stalk tastes a little bit sweet.
#人都可以吃的這個
It's edible.
#很小的時候
When I was a little kid,
#我們肚子餓的時候都吃過這個玉米秆
we used to eat the corn stalks when we were hungry.
#很香的哦
It smells good.
#挑大的砍 小的不要
We choose the big ones, not the small ones.
#我來找一根那個繩子來綁住
I'll fetch a piece of string to,
#把它綁回去
to tie them up.
#繩子都找不到
No string.
#唉 干脆用我的皮帶來
Ay! I'll just use my belt.
#用我的皮帶 把它摳出來
I use my belt. I take it out.
#這個不用皮帶都可以穿
This can be worn without a belt.
#你看 把這些玉米啊 給那小豬吃
Look! I am giving, giving the corns, to the piglets.
#快啦 一人一個哦
Come on! Everybody take one!
#照發 (他究竟在說甚麼.....^^")
Just throw.
#來
Come!
#不要搶哦
No scrambling!
#可能剛好一人一個
Perhaps everybody can get one.
#像水果一樣
It's like fruits.
#啊 現在這些豬都越來越漂亮啦
Ah! Now the pigs are getting more and more pretty.